本视频将被分为几个不同部分
For this video, which is going to be a few different sections
关于创建你的第一个关卡
will be about creating your first level,
本节介绍第一部分 创建关卡
in this case, with the first one, we're going to create the level,
我们将创建地形 喷涂地表
we're going to create the terrain, we're going to paint the terrain,
然后添加植物 全在这个视频中介绍完
and then we're going to apply vegetation, all within this one video.
所以时长大约10分钟 我们开始吧
So, it's only take about 10 minutes, and let's get to it.
点File菜单下New以创建关卡
To start, we'll go to File->New,
命名为training_FirstLVL
and we'll call this one training_FirstLVL,
让它保持在levels文件夹下 然后高度图分辨率调低
and we'll keep in the levels folder, then we're gonna choose a small heightmap resolution,
让地形长宽保持在128米
which means the terrain size will be 128 meters in all directions.
贴图尺寸保持在4k
We're going to keep the texture dimensions at 4k,
其他的就不用管了 那些跟压缩有关联
and not worry about the other settings, because they have to do with compression,
也不在本视频讨论范围内
and are out of this scope of this video.
我们点OK
We're gonna click ok,
现在我们有了128平方米的关卡
and now we're basically have our level which is 128,
我们拉到下面 会看到有海洋
and if we come down here, we have our ocean.
我们需要做的是 定义地形高度 以匹配海洋高度
So, what we need to do is we need to define the height of this terrain, so it matches the height of the ocean.
在地形编辑器中进入Edit->Set Terrain
Let's go into Edit->Set Terrain inside of the Terrain Editor box,
然后设置地形大约50米高
and we're gonna go to setting the terrain to something about 50 meters high.
我们会发现什么也没有发生 因为我们需要重新生成地形
We'll notice that nothing happened, and this is because we need to actually generate the terrain again.
我们把特征尺寸调低点 大约3.6
So let's bring the feature size down to about... 3.6 is fine,
崎岖度降到最低
we can lower the bumpiness all the way,
然后其他都保持默认
and everything else will keep at basic.
点OK
So if I click ok,
现在我们有了不错的小地形
we now have a nice little terrain.
我觉得这个地形还可以挽救一下 地形总是可以重新生成
I think I can actually get something a little better, so you can always go back and generate more,
你可以不断调试变量 重新生成
over and over again that if you wanna see the variation that you can create.
继续看看我们能得到什么地形
So let's go ahead and see what we can get again.
继续不断调整
So we keep getting blobs and blobs,
直到获得我们想要的地形
eventually, I want them will be about what I'm looking for.
这样就好了 两个小山丘
And, this will do. I kinda just want a more than just one, and kind of relatively small.
现在 我们有海洋 有岛屿
So now we have our ocean, and we have our island,
因为我们想要建个荒岛 对于新手来说这是最快
because that's what we're gonna do, is create a desert island, it's the easiest thing that you can do
最漂亮 最容易上手的
with the most aesthetically pleasing results quickly.
我现在要做的是降低这些隆起 它们太大了
What I need to do now is get rid of some of these humps, they're just too big.
在地形编辑器里 雕刻工具中 选Flatten
So, inside of the terrain editor, I can go to sculpt, and then we're choose Flantten,
我若开始涂抹
and if I were to just start painting,
它会显得有点随机 那不是理想效果
it would be kind of random and that's not what we want.
我们把半径降低到10 然后在高度这里
We're going to do is lower this down to 10 on the radius, and you'll see down here in the height,
我们可以选取高度
we can actually have the option to pick.
我们可以按住Ctrl键以动态选取高度
What we're actually going to do is to pick it dynamically by holding down the Ctrl key.
我们盯着这个地方 找个边缘选取高度
So if we keep our eyes peeled on this, so we click down here on the edge.
可以看见数值变成了所点的地方的高度
Maybe right there, we can see that it's switching based on where we click.
把它设置在大约18.6
So let's keep that up about 18.6,
拉近点 可以看见无论我们怎么雕刻
what we can do now is we can come in here and know that wherever we sculpt,
高度都不会低于这个数值
it's not gonna be below that level.
所以可以大胆雕刻
So we keep that, maybe do some over here,
现在我们想要平滑这些凸起
but now what if we want to actually smooth this out.
我们可以按Shift键
So we can press the Shift key,
现在我们可以平滑刚才雕刻过的地方
we now have the ability to smooth it out on everything we just sculpted.
或者平滑所有地方
So maybe we wanna smooth everything down,
现在我们有了更好的平面 更好的海滩
we can kinda have something that's a little bit better flattened, that way, we have a better beach.
现在 我们就创建好了陆地
So now that we have basically our landmass declared,
我们需要创建地表贴图 因为现在
we need to create a terrain texture to cover it, because right now
棋盘格只是默认贴图
the checkerboard look just isn't working.
我们进入绘涂工具 右键新建图层
So we go to paint, and I right click and create a layer,
命名为sandDry 干沙滩
let's call this one sandDry.
贴图选择为Textures/defaults下的white
And we're gonna choose the texture to be Textures/defaults, so we're just gonna choose white,
因为我们要喷涂沙子的贴图
because we want to paint the actual texture of sand.
所以我们打开材质
So we need to choose a material now,
选择materials/terrain下的beach_white_sand
and what we're gonna do is go to materials/terrain and choose beach_white_sand.
然后便可以在地表上涂抹
And what we can do is we can paint this in if we want,
你会注意到 喷涂之处会有很多沙子
so if we start painting, you'll notice right away, we get a lot of sand everywhere,
我们还可以改变沙子的颜色
and we can actually even change the color of it,
降低灰度 会使贴图变暗
drop it down and just grayscale, and you'll notice it's darker,
这也是我想要的效果
so maybe that's what we want.
效果看起来还不错
And this doesn't look bad actually.
我们不必一点点喷涂 其实有更省力的方法
So, instead of painting everything, we can actually cheat.
我们可以右键图层 选Flood Layer
We can right click this layer, and say Flood Layer,
整个地形便自动应用
and then automatically we have sand everywhere
效果还不错
which works pretty well.
美中不足的是 我还需要湿沙子
The one thing that I don't have is, I want to have a wet sand.
这里阴影看起来不太对
It doesn't look exactly right when we see some shadowing
沙子被冲走的效果也没有
but we don't see any change in how the sand kind of washes away.
所以我们需要另创建个图层
So what we can do is create another layer,
命名为sandWet 湿沙子
and call this one sandWet.
贴图改为Textures/defaults/white
And we can change the texture again, to be Textures/defaults/white again.
这次我们选个不同的材质
And then this time we're gonna choose a different material.
我们进入materials/terrain
So we go to materials/terrain
然后选择beach_white_sand_wet
and choose beach_white_sand_wet.
然后我们可以喷涂
We can go ahead and start painting this.
我要做的是喷涂上去 看看效果
So what I'ma do is I'm going to paint it in so we can see what we have,
有点太亮了 回去调整
it's a little bright, so if I can control it back,
想刚才那样降低明度
drop it like we did to the other,
这样就好了
and that'll work.
我刚才所做的只是校准
So all I did was calibrate it,
因为接下来我们要约束性程序化喷涂
because we're actually going to do a constraints procedurally painted.
回到雕刻工具 选择平化工具
Like before, with the sculpt, we can go back and we can flatten,
但关键在于我们要选取水位线浮动的高度
but the key thing understand this is we're actually going to pick the height of how far it influences.
水位在这个高度 假定它最高能浮动到这
So the water is here, let's say we influence up to this point here.
大约16.5
So let's try 16.5,
回到sandWet图层
so going back to sandWet,
我们可以设置最低高度和最高高度
we can set the minimum height with the maximum height.
我们在最高高度里填16.5
Let's go ahead and put this to 16.5 at the maximum height,
最低高度保持为0
and we leave the min height at zero.
然后右键图层选Flood Layer
So if I right click this now and flood layer,
会发现其被涂抹在所有边缘上
you'll notice that it's painted all around the edge of the actual ocean.
这个结果就已经很好了
Alright, I mean, you couldn't get any better because we're
因为我们还可以拿笔刷自己修饰
able to paint whatever we what along the edges
且不必担心有遗漏的地方
and not have to worry about whether or not it works,
因为我们已经基于高度自动生成了
because we procedurally generated it based on a height.
现在贴图就完成了
So now we've done that,
我们准备创建一些植被
we're ready go in and create some vegetation like we said.
这则需要我们进入Tools
So this right here is gonna require us to go to tools,
选择Vegataion Editor
and we'll go to the vegetation editor,
把这个拖到其它编辑器上方
and let's snap this over the other editor,
边缘往外拉点 我们要创建一些组
so I'm gonna bring this out a little bit, we're gonna create some groups.
第一组我要添加树木组
The first group I'm gonna do is I'm gonna add the trees group.
这个是最简单的
This is gonna be the easiest one to do,
也是最常见的
and probably the most densely populated one,
然后我们建另一个组叫Bushes
and then we're gonna do another group called Bushes,
放在下面
and that'll be the lower.
我们进入树木组
So if we go into this trees,
点击上面这里 这些图标和旧版本中的相同
we're gonna actually click up here, these are the same icons that we had before,
然后添加想要的树木
and we can click and add the actual trees we want.
这里我想要梧桐树
So what I want is I wanna have a palm tree,
我选择所有这些梧桐树 添加到组
and I'm gonna select all the palm trees in this group.
展开组 可以看见这些树
And if I scroll this open, we can see all of them,
这些树木都有相同的选项
and you would have the same selections on all the trees,
但这里我要选择组
but this time I'm actually gonna select the group,
这样可以影响组中所有的项目
and you can influence all the children of the parent group.
我们把尺寸变化率设为0.7
I'm going to change the size variation to be about point seven pass the size,
勾选旋转随机化
we'll do random rotation,
倾斜率设为1
and then in the bending, we're just gonna set that to 1,
拉到下面 在密度中 设置为7
we're gonna come down to the density and we're gonna change this to about 7 or so.
记住 这是树木之间的密度
Keep in mind this is the density between the actual instances,
所以数值越低密度越高
so the lower of the actual level,
这很反常 你会想
it's counterintuitive, you would think,
哦 密度 我想让密度更高
ok, density, I want it to be closer together.
所以我会提升这个值以创建更多物体 而不是降低
So what would I do, I wanna create more objects and you wouldn't increase it,
但实际上 这里的密度是指 物体之间的距离
but the density actually relies on the distance between those.
所以更高的值反而会使物体互相远离
So the higher the value the actually more spacing you get.
接下来最小高度设为18
We're gonna come in here as well and change this to 18 on the elevation minimum,
我们勾选投影
and then we're also going to change the cast shadow
勾选接收阴影 投影最小规格保持为低
and the receive shadow, we'll keep the min spec set to low.
然后我们保存下关卡
So let's save this real quick,
接下来我们右键 选择分布选定植被对象 然后看看效果
and then what we're gonna do is right click and distribute the selected vegetation objects and see what we get.
现在我们有很多树
So now we have a lot of trees,
随机生成得到处都是
all over the place that we just randomly generated,
看起来效果并不太糟
and to be honest it doesn't look that bad,
只是有点太多了
it's kind of a little bit too much,
所以我调整下
so maybe I want to go back and change it.
这里有不同的选项 选择我们的树
Well, there are different options that you have here, we can set our trees,
点击擦除按钮
and we can click the erase button,
便可手动擦除 效果也不错
and we can start erasing them manually which works quite well.
无论它是不是程序化生成的
It doesn't matter they were procedurally generated,
你都可以手动修改
you can come in and change that all around.
你也可以隐藏特定物种
You can also have the option to maybe hide the certain species,
或许这就是我要的效果
so maybe that's what we want.
我们可以显示这个 隐藏那个
We can do this, maybe hide that,
对于岛屿来说 这样看起来更可管理
and this looks a little bit more manageable as far as what the island is doing.
所以现在我们有了树
So we have all there trees in place,
这里不用的树 我们可以
and we have these other trees that maybe we can just
完全移除它们
completely get rid of if we want in.
所以我们选下面的Remove
So we go down to remove,
这样我们就不用处理它们
so now we don't deal with them at all.
回过头来 我们若想修改效果并分布更多植被
So let's look at this again, what if we want to just change this and distribute some more,
我们可以再点分布物体
so we can distribute more objects,
这是很好的主意 只需一键就能
and this is the nice idea of being able to use like
程序化或动态可变数量的生成
procedurally or dynamically changeable amounts
而不用自己一点点喷涂
just based on by clicking a button instead of going in and painting,
像之前所说 我们也可以手动喷涂
and like I said before, we can go in, we can paint the objects as well.
所以问题是 你想要什么样的树
So the question is what exactly do you want in your trees
以及你想如何动态分布它们
and how exactly do you want them to be dynamically pushed around.
现在我们准备刷灌木了
We're gonna go back and we're actually going to do bushes now.
我添加一些灌木
So I'm gonna add some bushes
进入natural下的bushes
and natural/bushes,
选择greenfernbush
and we're gonna choose greenfernbush.
我们选择所有这些
We're gonna select all of these,
做些跟之前类似的事情 设成0.7
and we're gonna do some of the similar things that we did on the other, point 7,
旋转 倾斜率为1
rotation, we're gonna set the bending to 1,
拉到下面 我们设置
we go ahead and move down, let's set the
最低高度为18
elevation minimum to 18,
勾选投影 接受阴影
cast shadow, receive shadow,
这样基本就设置好了
and then for the most part I think will be set
接下来 分布植被
to go ahead and distribute.
那么
So,
我发现密度我忘设了
the one thing that I realized I didn't set right before I click this was I didn't set the density.
所以你看 密度有多重要
So you can see how much it actually matters.
在密度未明确下 植被到处都是
With the density that's not declared, we now have bushes everywhere,
或许你想要这种效果 但这不是我想要的
which maybe what you wanted, but it's not what we wanted.
Ctrl+Z撤销 我们往下拉
So pressing ctrl+z, I can come down into the bushes,
设置密度到可控范围内
and I can set the density to something a little more manageable,
我们就设成6
so let's do that to 6
然后看看效果
and see what gets laid down.
现在我们有了少许灌木
So now we can see that we have quite a few more bushes,
但我想继续添加
but maybe we want to keep adding to them.
这样
So,
我们有这些可用的对象
we have all these objects that we would be able to use,
我还可以选择对象并修改
and now going into select, I can actually come in and change these too.
这是个功能 就像喷涂和移除
So it's just a feature like the paint and remove
你可以选择对象 并改变它们
that you would be able to select the objects that you're wanting to change,
还可以动态的修改
and being able to change them dynamically.
若我想要
If I want
所有这些对象都缩小
all these objects to be able to scale down,
我们也有方法可以做到
we have the option to do so.
像之前那样 我们可以缩减数量
And like before, we can also go in shrink this down
移除一些物种
and maybe remove some species.
所以你通常拿不准你想要什么
So you never know exactly what you want for something,
也许你想要灌木 也许不
maybe you want a lot of bushes or maybe you don't.
我们拉近点
We go in and we can
这里我们擦除一些对象
erase objects which we're gonna do in this case.
以后我们要放一些东西
We're gonna set something up so we can have like a little
放一些桥 台阶之类的
bridge later, stages of this.
目前为止 我们有刚放好的植被
But for right now, we have the vegetation, we have just laid it,
我想视频到这就结束了
and I think I'm gonna end the video there
接下来我们要介绍全局光照 设置好云
just before we start getting in to the actual global illumination and set in the clouds up,
然后放置一些对象 也许放个小
and then sticking an object right here and maybe a nice little
em...
船坞 可以进出海
dock that we could have out into the ocean, so
这期视频介绍了如何创建植被
this is a video showing you how to set up the vegetation,
如何动态的创建
how to set up everything dynamically
以及现场快速调整参数
and change around the actual parameters on the fly quickly,
这也是最重要的部分
which is the most important part.
翻译：他出院了